[
  {
    "question": "The clause used to filter rows is _______",
    "answer": "WHERE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to group rows is _______",
    "answer": "GROUP BY"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to filter groups is _______",
    "answer": "HAVING"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to sorts rows is _______",
    "answer": "ORDER BY"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to removes duplicates is _______",
    "answer": "DISTINCT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to retrieve only specific columns from a table is _______",
    "answer": "SELECT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to skip a number of rows before returning the result is _______",
    "answer": "OFFSET"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to get only specific columns from a table is _______",
    "answer": "SELECT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The _______ clause is used to specify the table from which data is retrieved.",
    "answer": "FROM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to filter rows before grouping is _______",
    "answer": "WHERE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The clause used to filter groups after aggregation is _______",
    "answer": "HAVING"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SQL statement type used to create tables is _______ (DDL/DML/DRL)",
    "answer": "DDL"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SQL statement type used to retrieve data is _______ (DDL/DML/DRL)",
    "answer": "DRL"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SQL statement type used to insert data is _______ (DDL/DML/DRL)",
    "answer": "DML"
  },
  {
    "question": "The data type used to take the fixed character set is _______",
    "answer": "CHAR"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operator used to compare two values for equality is _______",
    "answer": "="
  },
  {
    "question": "The operator used to select values within a range is _______",
    "answer": "BETWEEN"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operator used for pattern matching is _______",
    "answer": "LIKE"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operator used to match multiple values in a list is _______",
    "answer": "IN"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operator used to check the data matching is _______",
    "answer": "LIKE"
  }
]